<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Migrating From AQ :: Transactional Event Queues</title>
    <link>https://oracle.github.io/microservices-datadriven/transactional-event-queues/aq-migration/index.html</link>
    <description>Oracle Database 23ai includes a migration path from Advanced Queuing (AQ) to Transactional Event Queues (TxEventQ), to take advantage of enhanced performance and scalability for event-driven architectures.&#xA;Advanced Queuing (AQ) has been Oracle’s database messaging system for managing asynchronous communication in enterprise applications, allowing reliable queuing and message delivery. TxEventQ leverages Kafka-based event queuing, offering improved throughput, lower latency, and greater scalability, making it ideal for modern event-driven architectures and high-volume event processing.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://oracle.github.io/microservices-datadriven/transactional-event-queues/aq-migration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AQ Migration</title>
      <link>https://oracle.github.io/microservices-datadriven/transactional-event-queues/aq-migration/migration/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oracle.github.io/microservices-datadriven/transactional-event-queues/aq-migration/migration/index.html</guid>
      <description>This section provides a detailed guide for migrating from Oracle Advanced Queuing (AQ) to Transactional Event Queues (TxEventQ). The migration process uses the DBMS_AQMIGTOOL package to ensure minimal disruption of existing messaging workflows.&#xA;Users of AQ are recommended to migrate to TxEventQ for increased support, performance, and access to new database features. It is recommended to read through the document fully before attempting migration.&#xA;DBMS_AQMIGTOOL Overview Migration Workflow Checking Compatibility Initiating Migration Checking Migration Status Commit the Migration Checking and Handling Migration Errors Cancelling and Recovering Migration Limitations and Workarounds DBMS_AQMIGTOOL Overview The migration tool interface provides the following functionalities:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>