<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Oracle Backend for Spring Boot and Microservices</title>
    <link>https://oracle.github.io/microservices-datadriven/spring/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Oracle Backend for Spring Boot and Microservices</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://oracle.github.io/microservices-datadriven/spring/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://oracle.github.io/microservices-datadriven/spring/development/setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oracle.github.io/microservices-datadriven/spring/development/setup/</guid>
      <description>This page provides details on how to set up your development environment to work with Oracle Backend for Spring Boot and Microservices.
The following platforms are recommended for a development environment:
Microsoft Windows 10 or 11, preferrably with Windows Subsystem for Linux 2 macOS (11 or later recommended) on Intel or Apple silicon Linux, for example Oracle Linux, Ubuntu, and so on. The following tools are recommended for a development environment:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Structure</title>
      <link>https://oracle.github.io/microservices-datadriven/spring/development/project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oracle.github.io/microservices-datadriven/spring/development/project/</guid>
      <description>To take advantage of the built-in platform services, Oracle recommends using the following project structure.
Recommended versions:
Spring Boot 3.1.6 Spring Cloud 2022.0.4 Java 17 or 21 Table of Contents:
Dependencies Spring Application Configuration Data Sources Liquibase Oracle Transaction Manager for Microservices Spring Config Server Dependencies Oracle recommends adding the following dependencies to your application so that it can take advantage of the built-in platform services. For example:
&amp;lt;properties&amp;gt; &amp;lt;project.build.sourceEncoding&amp;gt;UTF-8&amp;lt;/project.build.sourceEncoding&amp;gt; &amp;lt;java.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
