<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Development on Oracle Backend for Microservices and AI</title>
    <link>https://oracle.github.io/microservices-datadriven/spring/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Development on Oracle Backend for Microservices and AI</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://oracle.github.io/microservices-datadriven/spring/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Development Environment Setup</title>
      <link>https://oracle.github.io/microservices-datadriven/spring/development/setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oracle.github.io/microservices-datadriven/spring/development/setup/</guid>
      <description>This page provides details on how to set up your development environment to work with Oracle Backend for Microservices and AI.&#xA;The following platforms are recommended for a development environment:&#xA;Microsoft Windows 10 or 11, preferably with Windows Subsystem for Linux 2 macOS (11 or later recommended) on Intel or Apple silicon Linux, for example Oracle Linux, Ubuntu, and so on. The following tools are recommended for a development environment:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predefined Variables</title>
      <link>https://oracle.github.io/microservices-datadriven/spring/development/envvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oracle.github.io/microservices-datadriven/spring/development/envvars/</guid>
      <description>When you deploy a Spring Boot application using the Oracle Backend for Microservices and AI CLI or Visual Code extension, a number of predefined environment variables will be injected into the pod definition. You may reference any of these variables in your application.&#xA;The predefined variables are as follows:&#xA;app.container.port, for example 8080.&#xA;This sets the listen port for the pod and service. The Spring Boot application will listen on this port.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project Structure</title>
      <link>https://oracle.github.io/microservices-datadriven/spring/development/project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oracle.github.io/microservices-datadriven/spring/development/project/</guid>
      <description>To take advantage of the built-in platform services, Oracle recommends using the following project structure.&#xA;Recommended versions:&#xA;Spring Boot 3.3.x Spring Cloud 2023.x.x Java 21 (or 17) Table of Contents:&#xA;Dependencies Spring Application Configuration Data Sources Liquibase Oracle Transaction Manager for Microservices Spring Config Server Tracing Dependencies Oracle recommends adding the following dependencies to your application so that it can take advantage of the built-in platform services. For example:&#xA;&amp;lt;properties&amp;gt; &amp;lt;project.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
